As darkness falls, the last dragon will choose its rider.
Eragon is a fantasy, action, adventure film directed by Stefen Fangmeier.
In his homeland of Alagaesia, a farm boy happens upon a dragon's egg -- a discovery that leads him on a
predestined journey where he realized he's the one person who can defend his home against an evil king.
Eragon, played by Ed Speleers.
Brom, played by Jeremy Irons.
Arya, played by Sienna Guillory.
Durza, played by Robert Carlyle.
King Galbatorix, played by John Malkovich.
Murtagh, played by Garrett Hedlund.
Eragon (stylized in all lowercase) is a 2006 fantasy adventure film directed by Stefen Fangmeier (in his directorial
debut) and written by Peter Buchman, loosely based on Christopher Paolini's 2002 novel of the same name.
It stars Ed Speleers in the title role as well as Jeremy Irons, Sienna Guillory, Robert Carlyle, Djimon
Hounsou, Garrett Hedlund, Joss Stone, and John Malkovich, with Rachel Weisz as Saphira the dragon.
The film also marked the film debuts for Speleers and Stone.
Principal photography took place at the Mafilm Fót Studios
in Hungary, starting on August 1, 2005.
Visual effects and animation were provided by Industrial
Light & Magic, Weta Digital and Cinesite.
Eragon was released worldwide on December 15, 2006, by 20th Century Fox.
It received widespread negative reviews from critics and book fans, who criticized its acting, screenplay, visuals and
unfaithfulness to the source material, though its CGI and the performances of Speleers and Irons were praised by a few critics.
It was the 10th worst reviewed film of 2006 on Rotten Tomatoes, but
the 31st highest-grossing film of 2006 in the US.
The film was released for home entertainment on March 20, 2007.
Originally, Eragon was supposed to be the first in a franchise based on Paolini's Inheritance
Cycle book series, with Fangmeirer shooting both Eldest and Brisingr back-to-back.
However, following the poor critical reception of Eragon on its release, and its
box-office performance,  the planned sequels were not produced.
The film explores themes of princess, based on
novel or book, elves, magic, kingdom.